Guide to the Partners for Livable Communities collection, 1962-1994
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 9: Open Spaces, Parks, and Recreation, 1971-1990; (3 boxes)
  - Saint Paul Riverfront Initiative: The first five years, 1984-1989 (Box 30, Volume 27)
    Department of Planning and Economic Development
  - Social and Recreational Amenities in the Downtown, 1982 (Box 31, Volume 1)
    Verna Semotuk, Consultant, City of Vancouver Social Planning Department
  - St. Petersburg Waterfront Plan, 1980 (Box 31, Volume 2)
    Department of Community Development
  - State of the Trees, 1982 (Box 31, Volume 3)
    Department of Engineering
  - Staging a Renaissance on the Waterfront, 1980 (Box 31, Volume 4)
    Mitchell L. Moss
  - Tampa's Lowry Park Zoological Garden Master Plan, 1984 (Box 31, Volume 5)
  - Tennessee Riverpark: Chattanooga, 1985 (Box 31, Volume 6)
  - Trends Vol. 18, No. 4: Trends in Urban Forestry, 1981 (Box 31, Volume 7)
    Park Practice Program
  - Urban Foresters Notebook, 1978 (Box 31, Volume 8)
    Silas Little, editor
  - Urban Forestry in Dayton, Ohio, 1982 (Box 31, Volume 9)
  - Urban Forestry of San Diego, 1982 (Box 31, Volume 10)
    Center City Association, San Diego, California
  - Urban Park and Recreation Recovery Program: Impact Report 1978-1983, 1985 (Box 31, Volume 11)
    Ann Breen
  - Urban Waterfront Development, ca. 1980 (Box 31, Volume 12)
    Douglas M. Wrenn, Associate, Urban Land Institute
  - Urban waterfronts '83: Balancing Public/Private Interests: a summary of a conference on Sept 30-Oct 1, 1983, in Washington, D.C., 1986 (Box 31, Volume 13)
  - Urban waterfronts '84: Toward New Horizons: a summary of a conference on September 14-15, 1984, in Washington, D.C. (Box 31, Volume 14)
  - Urban Waterfront Restoration: the opportunity, the benefits, the need for support, 1981 (Box 32, Volume 1)
  - Urban Waterfront Revitalization: the role of recreation and heritage, ca. 1978 (Box 32, Volume 2)
    Heritage Conservation and Recreation Service
  - Waterfront: America's Ugly Duckling Tale, 1980 (Box 32, Volume 3)
    Patricia Weil, Frances Fifs, and Kristina Goodrich
  - Waterfront at Berkeley: Santa Fe's Concept for the Eastshore, undated (Box 32, Volume 4)
  - Why Not Start with the Children, undated (Box 32, Volume 5)
    Neighborhood Preservation Project, Arcade, New York
- Series 10: Public and Private Partnerships, 1976-1989; (2 boxes)
  This series includes reports and studies on the projects of various public and private partnerships aimed at developing the local economy, mitigating social inequity, and providing social services such as child care and urban renewal to the community. The partnerships examined in this seris include the Bronx Land Reclamation Program, the Citibank Flatbrush Project, the Missouri Neighborhood Assistance Program, and the Navy Broadway Complex Project.
  - 1983-1984 All-America cities book of finalist entries (Box 32, Volume 6)
  - Bronx Land Reclamation Program: a demonstration in large scale land treatment and public/private cooperation, 1982 (Box 32, Volume 7)
    New York City Open Space Coalition, Inc.
  - Commercial Revitalization in Flatbush: Citibank Flatbush Pilot Project, 1982 (Box 32, Volume 8)
    Economic Development Assistance Consortium
  - Corporate Child Care, 1987 (Box 32, Volume 9)
    Shelley Smith
  - Establishing and operating private sector development organizations, 1984 (Box 32, Volume 10)
    National Council for Urban Economic Development
  - Ives Street Revitalization Area, undated (Box 32, Volume 11)
    Office of the Mayor, City of Danbury, Connecticut
  - Joint development Marketplace, 1978 (Box 32, Volume 12)
  - Joint development of transit properties, 1987 (Box 32, Volume 13)
    Geraldine Bachman
  - Local Iniatives Support Corporation: a private-public venture for community and neighborhood revitalization, 1980 (Box 32, Volume 14)
  - Missouri neighborhood assistance program: a successful business/community partnership, 1981 (Box 32, Volume 15)
    Mary Beth Gordon
  - National Main Street Center Training Program, undated (Box 32, Volume 16)
    National Trust for Historic Preservation
  - Navy Broadway complex project, 1985 (Box 32, Volume 17)
  - Neighborhood Reinvestment Partnership: A case study of Aetna's National Urban Neighborhood Investment Program, 1982 (Box 32, Volume 18)
    Jerold Altman
  - Neighborhood self-help program, 1984 (Box 32, Volume 19)
  - New Civics No. 7: Community Service Partnerships, undated (Box 32, Volume 20)
    Milton Kotler
  - New Civics No. 17: Community Development Partnerships, undated (Box 33, Volume 1)
    Nelson Rosenbaum and Milton Kotler
  - New perspectives on community development, 1976 (Box 33, Volume 2)
    Mahlon Apgar, editor
  - Pain of the Cities: Options for Foundations, 1982 (Box 33, Volume 3)
    Craig Smith
  - Planner's role in facilitating private sector reinvestment, 1979 (Box 33, Volume 4)
    Dennis R. Marino
  - Public, private efforts revitalize Grand Avenue: Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1983 (Box 33, Volume 5)
    Jon L. Wellhoefer
  - Public-private partnership: An opportunity for urban communities, 1982 (Box 33, Volume 6)
    Research and Policy Committee for Economic Development
  - Public-private partnership in American cities: seven case studies, 1982 (Box 33, Volume 7)
    R. Scott Fosler and Renee A. Berger
  - Public-private partnerships: improving urban life, 1986 (Box 33, Volume 8)
    Perry Davis
  - Rebuilding of an American neighborhood: a report on how your ordinary bank deposits can help this extraordinary project, 1980? (Box 33, Volume 9)
  - Recent Suburbanization of Blacks: how much, who, and where?, 1979 (Box 33, Volume 10)
  - Reviving cities with tax abatement, 1980 (Box 33, Volume 11)
    Daniel R. Mandelker
  - San Diego newspaper coverage of Navy plans for Broadway complex, 1989 (Box 33, Volume 12)
  - Strategies for Cities and Counties: a strategic planning guide, undated (Box 33, Volume 13)
    Donna L. Sorkin, Nancy B. Ferris, and James Hudak
  - Summary Research Report: Integrating Public Art and Private Development, 1987 (Box 33, Volume 14)
    Bill Flood
  - Technology, Innovation, and Regional Economic Development, 1984 (Box 33, Volume 15)
    U.S. Office of Technology Assessment
  - Urban Development and Investment: Public and Private Co-operation, 1983 (Box 34, Volume 1)
    Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development
  - Urban Development and Urban Conservation: Conflict and Accomodation, 1978 (Box 34, Volume 2)
    Joint Development Marketplace
  - Urban Revitalization through Public-Private Cooperation in Lafayette, Indiana, 1982 (Box 34, Volume 3)
    T. William Patterson
  - WECO story, 1980 (Box 34, Volume 4)
    Wendell W. Phillips, Woodland East Community Organization
- Series 11: Tourism, 1965-1990; (1 box)
  This series contains reports and proposals pertaining to the promotion and development of tourism. The materials deal with such topics as the development of historic centers for tourism, the 1980 and 1981 Travel Outlook Forum proceedings, tourist impact control, the promotion of black material culture, and the "gritty city enhancement strategy," which aims to capitalize on the the "gritty" ambience of old working-class neighborhoods and industrial centers as tourist attractions.
  - 1980 Travel Outlook Forum proceedings: November 29, 1979, Hyatt Regency Washington, Washington, D.C. (Box 34, Volume 5)
    Travel Outlook Forum (1980)
  - 1981 Travel Outlook Forum proceedings: December 4, 1980, Loew's L'Enfant Plaza Hotel, Washington, D.C. (Box 34, Volume 6)
    Travel Outlook Forum (1981)
  - Challenge of Leisure: The Fourth Wave, 1965 (Box 34, Volume 7)
    Civic Trust, Scotland and Whales
  - Comprehensive plan for the national capital visitors to the national capital, 1984 (Box 34, Volume 8)
    National Capital Planning Commission
  - Controlling Tourism Impact, 1980 (Box 34, Volume 9)
    S. Henry Edmunds
  - Cultural tourism and Gritty City Enhancement Strategy, 1980 (Box 34, Volume 10)
    Ronald Lee Fleming, President, Townscape Institute
  - Discovering new sources for cultural tourism: Black material culture offers fresh approach to marketing tourism, 1982 (Box 34, Volume 11)
    Everett L. Fly and La Barbara Wigfall Fly
  - E-Ways: hooking up our resources, part I, 1979 (Box 34, Volume 12)
    Environmental Awareness Center, University of Wisconsin, Madison
  - Leisure and Touring, 6th Congress on: the motorist and the environment, 1977 (Box 34, Volume 13)
    International Touring Alliance
  - Preservation, rehabilitation and touristic development of the historic core of Quito: final report, 1974 (Box 34, Volume 14)
    James Marston Fitch
  - Steamboatin' 1985: Delta Queen, Mississippi Queen: the last great American adventure (Box 34, Volume 15)
  - Tacoma beautiful, undated (Box 34, Volume 16)
  - Tourism and Urban Development, 1982 (Box 34, Volume 17)
    Community and Economic Development Task Force
  - Tourism as a tool for urban community redevelopment: an integrated planning approach, 1990 (Box 34, Volume 18)
    Kate Brower, Graduate Thesis, Columbia University
  - Tourist traffic in small historic cities: analysis, strategies and recommendations. Executive Summary, 1976 (Box 35, Volume 1)
    Roger F. Teal
  - Tourist traffic in small historic cities: analysis, strategies and recommendations. Final report, 1976 (Box 35, Volume 2)
- Series 12: Transportation, 1962-1990; (6.5 boxes)
  This series contains materials on the design and improvement of transportation infrastructure. Most of the studies cover general topics, but the series includes case studies of New York, New Orleans, Los Angeles, and the Netherlands. The topics covered include automobile restricted zones, center-city parking and parking lot design, transportation architecture, the economics of transportation restriction, traffic control design, railway and trolley transit, bicycle transportation and parking, and pedestrian relief areas.
  - 1978 federally coordinated program of highway research and development (Box 35, Volume 3)
    U.S. Federal Highway Administration
  - 1981 federal highway legislation: federal finance options, 1980 (Box 35, Volume 4)
  - Aesthetics in Transportation, 1980 (Box 35, Volume 5)
    Lajos Heder
  - Aesthetics in transportation: guidelines for incorporating design, art and architecture into transportation facilities, 1980 (Box 35, Volume 6)
    Moore-Heder Architects
  - Aesthetics in transportation. Executive summary: guidelines for incorporating design, art and architecture into transportation.., 1980 (Box 35, Volume 7)
  - Architecture of transport in the Federal Republic of Germany, 1981 (Box 35, Volume 8)
    Karlhans Muller
  - Arts on the line: a pilot project in arts and transportation, 1980 (Box 35, Volume 9)
  - Arts on the line: art for public transit spaces, 1980 (Box 35, Volume 10)
    Cambridge Arts Council (MA)
  - Auto restricted zone/multi-user vehicle system study: final report. Technical appendix, Boston, 1977 (Box 35, Volume 11)
    Alan M. Voorhees and Associates
  - Auto restricted zone/multi-user vehicle system study: final report. Technical appendix, Burlington, 1977 (Box 35, Volume 12)
  - Auto restricted zone/multi-user vehicle system study: final report. Vol. I, Auto restricted zones: background and feasibility, 1977 (Box 35, Volume 13)
  - Auto restricted zone/multi-user vehicle system study: final report. Vol. III, Plans for five cities, 1977 (Box 35, Volume 14)
  - Auto restricted zone/multi-user vehicle system study: final report. Vol. IV, Site selection methodology, 1977 (Box 35, Volume 15)
  - Bicycle parking, 1983 (6th ed.) (Box 35, Volume 16)
    Ellen Fletcher
  - Business community attitudes toward transportation: a survey of the region, 1978 (Box 36, Volume 1)
    Port Authority of New York and New Jersey
  - Car drivers test public transportation: a measure to encourage persons to switch to public transportation, 1983 (Box 36, Volume 2)
    Werner Brog and Otto G. Forg
  - Case for rail transit, 1978 (Box 36, Volume 3)
    American Public Transportation Association
  - Center city environment and transportation: local government solutions, 1977 (Box 36, Volume 4)
    Public Technology, Inc.
  - Central area parking and loading study: final recommendations report, 1980 (Box 36, Volume 4)
    Toronto, Ontario Commissioner of Public Works
  - Central area parking and loading study, Response to the, 1980 (Box 36, Volume 5)
  - Central Washington transportation and civic design study: a summary of a feasibility study, 1977 (Box 36, Volume 6)
    Joseph Passonneau and Partners
  - Cities and automobile dependence: a sourcebook, 1989 (Box 36, Volume 7)
    Peter W. G. Newman
  - City and the Arts: A Civic Handbook of Grants Programs Offered by The National Endowment for the Arts, 1980 (Box 36, Volume 8)
  - City Cars, Transport and Amenity In Urban Places: A Reader, 1990 (Box 36, Volume 9)
  - Culture stations project, 1982 (Box 36, Volume 10)
    New York City Metropolitan Transportation Authority
  - Delight of a city: Parking (section of article from Concrete Quarterly no. 99), 1973 (Box 36, Volume 11)
    George Perkin
  - Design, art and architecture in transportation: 2nd annual report to the Secretary of Transportation, 1979 (Box 36, Volume 12)
    U.S. Department of Transportation. Task Force on Design, Art ...
  - Design, art and architecture in transportation: first annual report to the Secretary of Transportation, 1978 (Box 36, Volume 13)
  - Design for transportation national awards program, 1982 (Box 36, Volume 14)
    Community Design Exchange
  - Designing effective pedestrian improvements in business districts, 1982 (Box 36, Volume 15)
  - Development of bicycle transportation in selected areas of the Federal Republic of Germany between 1975/76 and 1980/81, 1981 (Box 36, Volume 16)
    Werner Brog and Ehrhard Erl
  - Dimensions of parking, 1979 (Box 36, Volume 17)
    Parking Consultants Council
  - Downtown circulation and Northbank parking analysis, Flint, Michigan, 1980 (Box 37, Volume 1)
    Flint, Mich. Downtown Development Authority
  - Ecological Approach to Highway Landscape Design, 1977 (Box 37, Volume 2)
    Paul Tritenbach
  - Economic impacts of transportation restraints, 1980 (Box 37, Volume 3)
  - Economics of urban transportation, 1979 (Box 37, Volume 4)
    Mark W. Frankena
  - Flexible parking requirements, 1982 (Box 37, Volume 5)
  - Foot notes, undated (Box 37, Volume 6)
    Columbia University Center for Advanced Research in Urban and Environmental Affairs
  - Future of the trolley: end of the line or a new beginning?, 1981 (Box 37, Volume 7)
    Richard E. Nathan
  - Future of Rail Transit, 1978 (Box 37, Volume 8)
    American Public Transit Association
  - Handbook for motor vehicle noise enforcement, 1980 (Box 37, Volume 9)
    Gale R. Hruska
  - Heavy lorries: a civic trust report, 1970 (Box 37, Volume 10)
    Civic Trust
  - Heavy lorries: a civic trust report: nine years on, 1979 (Box 37, Volume 11)
  - Highway guide signs: a framework for design and evaluation, 1977 (Box 37, Volume 12)
    J. Paul Dean
  - How to save your own street, 1981 (Box 37, Volume 13)
    Raquel Ramati
  - How to unclog midtown traffic, 1977 (Box 37, Volume 14)
  - Improving the residential street environment: final report, 1981 (Box 37, Volume 15)
    Daniel T. Smith
  - Increasing design and art in local transportation, 1980 (Box 37, Volume 16)
    New England Municipal Center
  - Innovations in urban transportation in Europe and their transferability to the United States..., 1980 (Box 37, Volume 17)
    Howard J. Simkowitz
  - Landslide transportation at ports: a preliminary assessment of transportation connectivity problems at U.S. ports, 1980 (Box 37, Volume 18)
  - Land use and transportation: basic theory, 1973 (Box 38, Volume 1)
    Douglass B. Lee
  - Livable streets for the downtown neighborhood: a plan to improve and protect the residential street environment in downtown Santa Cruz, 1981 (Box 38, Volume 2)
    Jeff Oberdorfer and Associates
  - Livable urban streets: managing auto traffic in neighborhoods: final report, 1976 (Box 38, Volume 3)
    Donald Appleyard and Sue M. Gerson
  - Manhattan without cars? (article from New York Affairs), 1973 (Box 38, Volume 4)
    Harry Schwartz
  - Methods of traffic limitation in urban areas: inquiry into the impact of the motor vehicle on the environment, 1972 (Box 38, Volume 5)
    J. Michael Thompson
  - Modernizing rail transit for today's city, 1979 (Box 38, Volume 6)
  - Motorist and the environment: Manila, Philippines, 5th-9th December 1977: final report (Box 38, Volume 7)
    AIT Congress on Leisure and Touring (6th: 1977)
  - Motorists understanding of traffic control devices: test II, 1980 (Box 38, Volume 8)
    Slade Hulbert and Paul Fowler
  - Nation in motion: historic American transportation sites, 1976 (Box 38, Volume 9)
    Elizabeth Rogers
  - New approaches in state transportation planning: prepared for presentation at the 58th annual meeting, Transportation Research Board..., 1979 (Box 38, Volume 10)
    Neil Wilson
  - New Orleans central business district traffic study, 1970 (Box 38, Volume 11)
    Bureau of Governmental Research
  - Northern Peninsula Highway zoning study, 1979-1984 (Box 38, Volume 12)
    Canada Development Control Division
  - Notebook 1: Identification of Transportation Alternatives (Environment assessment notebook series), 1975 (Box 38, Volume 13)
    Skidmore, Owings and Merrill
  - Notebook 2: Social Impacts (Environment assessment notebook series), 1975 (Box 38, Volume 14)
  - Notebook 3: Economic Impacts (Environment assessment notebook series), 1975 (Box 39, Volume 1)
  - Notebook 4: Physical Impacts (Environment assessment notebook series), 1975 (Box 39, Volume 2)
  - Notebook 5: Organization of Content of Environmental Assessment Materials (Environment assessment notebook series), 1975 (Box 39, Volume 3)
  - On changing automobile and parking staff sizes, 1983 (Box 39, Volume 4)
    Richard F. Roti
  - Parking construction in 1976, 1977 (Box 39, Volume 5)
    Norene Dann Martin
  - Parking facilities for industrial plants, 1969 (Box 39, Volume 6)
    Institute of Traffic Engineers
  - Parking lot design from the Development guide for the city of Akron, ca. 1980 (Box 39, Volume 7)
    Akron, Ohio. Divisions of Design and Zoning
  - Parking management: a report of the Transportation Task Force of the Urban Consortium for Technology Initiatives, 1978 (Box 39, Volume 8)
    Urban Consortium for Technology Initiatives
  - Parking: North Side Neighborhood Preservation Study, 1978 (Box 39, Volume 9)
    Victoria Williams
  - Parking planning: municipalities come up with innovations in the search for smoother traffic flows, 1971 (Box 39, Volume 10)
    Ronald J. Lenney
  - Parking space goes further at multi-use projects: shared parking for retail and office space can mean substantial savings for developers, 1976 (Box 39, Volume 11)
    Michael G. Ferreri
  - Pedestrian precincts in Britain, 1981 (Box 39, Volume 12)
    John Roberts
  - Pedestrian relief areas (PRA): history, literature survey case study analysis and design criteria, 1977 (Masters Thesis) (Box 39, Volume 13)
    Nikki DiVette
  - Pedestrian relief areas (PRA): history, literature survey case study analysis and design criteria, 1977 (Masters Thesis) (Box 40, Volume 1)
  - People movement for downtown improvement, 1977 (Box 40, Volume 2)
    Institute of Public Administration
  - Platforms for design, undated (Box 40, Volume 3)
    Louis Chapin
  - Potential of the bicycle as a substitute for other modes of transportation, 1983 (Box 40, Volume 4)
    Werner Brog and Erhard Erl
  - Principles of off-street parking and loading for industry, 1962 (Box 40, Volume 5)
    National Industrial Zoning Committee
  - Proceedings of First Downtown People Movers Workshop: project management and control, Apr. 30-May 2, 1978 (Morgantown, West Virginia) (Box 40, Volume 6)
    Downtown People Mover Workshop (1st: 1978)
  - Proceedings [of the] International Symposium on Neighborhood Traffic Restraits, 1981 (Box 40, Volume 7)
    International Symposium on Neighborhood Traffic Restraits
  - Project CORE: a proposal for the development of community-oriented roadway environments, 1979 (Box 40, Volume 8)
    Yonkers, N.Y. Department of Community Development
  - Prospects for the automobile: sputtering toward the twenty-first century, 1980 (Box 40, Volume 9)
    Steve Olson
  - Rapid recovery: feasibility report, undated (Box 40, Volume 10)
    Rapid Recovery, Inc.
  - Reestablishing the link: a study of the commuter rail station, 1970 (Box 40, Volume 11)
    Anthony R. Sloan
  - Relationship of accident frequency to travel exposure: paper presented at the 60th annual meeting ... Transportation Research Board..., 1981 (Box 40, Volume 12)
    Werner Brog and Bernd Kuffner
  - Resolves of the Monterey Conference on Planning for Rotorcraft and Commuter Air Transportation, 1981 (Box 40, Volume 13)
    U.S. National Aeronautics and Space Administration
  - Return of the trolley: cities across the country are putting streetcars back in service and adding vitality to downtown areas, 1983 (Box 40, Volume 14)
    Richard Herbert
  - Role of transportation in urban planning, development and environment, 1974 (Box 40, Volume 15)
    Federal German Ministry of Regional Planning
  - Scenic Highways Plan, 1979 (Box 41, Volume 1)
    Department of City Planning, Los Angeles, California
  - Second battle of New Orleans: a history of the Vieux Carre Riverfront Expressway controversy, 1981 (Box 41, Volume 2)
    Richard O. Baubach
  - Sociedad de Aparcamientos de Barcelona, S. A., 1978 (Box 41, Volume 3)
  - Study of Airports: Designb, Art and Architecture, 1981 (Box 41, Volume 4)
    Donald P. Bowman
  - Synthesis of literature on transportation/economic development, 1980 (Box 41, Volume 5)
    James E. Peterson and the National Council for Urban Economic Development
  - Taming automobiles in neighborhoods, 1980 (Box 41, Volume 6)
    Cynthia Whitehead
  - Taxicab in transportation: a bibliography, undated (Box 41, Volume 7)
    U.S. Technology Sharing Office
  - Techniques for acquiring open space at less-than-fee: a guide for local officials, 1982 (Box 41, Volume 8)
  - Transit + information referral system: downtown development district final report, 1980 (Box 41, Volume 9)
    Downtown Development District, New Orleans
  - Transit station joint development: final report, 1973 (Box 41, Volume 10)
  - Transport policy and the development of the transportation network in the Netherlands, undated (Box 41, Volume 11)
  - Transport tomorrow: a national priority. I, Transportation: forces of change, 1981 (Box 41, Volume 12)
    Paul O. Roberts
  - Transportation planning as if people mattered, 1979 (Box 41, Volume 13)
    C. Kenneth Orski
  - Transportation planning as if people mattered: address by C. Kenneth Orski ... before the San Antonio town meeting, March 17, 1978 (Box 41, Volume 14)
  - Transportation system management: urban transportation for the eighties, 1980 (Box 41, Volume 15)
  - Use of urban public transportation for multiperson trips and the market chances of a family tariff, undated (Box 41, Volume 16)
    Werner Brog and Erhart Erl
  - Where are we going? Kentucky transportation in 1980 (Box 41, Volume 17)
    Sandra Kolichman
  - Woonerf, 1980 (Box 41, Volume 18)
    Royal Dutch Touring Club
  - Woonerf, a different approach to environmental management in residential areas and the related traffic legislation, 1977 (Box 41, Volume 19)
  - Woonerf, a new approach to environmental management in residential areas and the related traffic legislation, 1980 (Box 41, Volume 20)
  - Woonerf, an environment for man and transport together, 1978 (Box 41, Volume 21)
- Series 13: Urban Planning, 1956-1994; (11 boxes)